discovery.co.za 2006-09-24

# Discovery - Health · Life · Vitality

Please Note: By visiting Discovery.co.za, you are accepting the practices described in the Privacy and Security Policy.

This Privacy Policy applies to the Discovery Group comprising of the following companies namely; Discovery Holdings Limited, Discovery Health (Pty) Limited, Discovery Life Limited, Vitality HealthStyle (Pty) Ltd, Vitality Travel (Pty) Limited and Destiny Health Incorporated (collectively hereinafter referred to as 'Discovery').

Discovery understands the importance of privacy and is committed to creating a site that can be used securely. Please read our Privacy and Security policy to find out what practices we employ to protect your information. 

As a client and user of Discovery.co.za, you authorise Discovery to collect and process personal information obtained by Discovery through any means to use this information in accordance with the terms and conditions set out in this Policy.

top

We gather individually identifiable information from you such as your personal details, and movements within the site.

top

The information is used:

  * for marketing purposes within Discovery; 
  * to obtain additional information that we may not have for critical business purposes.
  * for internal purposes such as the updating of Discovery's records.

In the event of Discovery wishing to use your information for purposes other as set out herein, Discovery undertakes to obtain your permission.

top

By registering on Discovery.co.za you enable us to verify who you are and can ensure that your information is protected. We will ask you to supply a few personal details for identification purposes to facilitate future communication with you. For security purposes, one of our call center agents will call you once you have registered to verify the details supplied.

top

Discovery.co.za is specially designed to meet the needs of Discovery clients. As a client of Discovery, you have access to all servicing on Discovery.co.za. However, should you terminate your membership with Discovery Health or Life, your access to the Discovery.co.za site will only be granted for two months following the termination, where after you will no longer have access.

top

With the use of the best encryption technology in the industry - 128 bit SSL (Secure Socket Layer) we can encrypt the connection between you and Discovery.co.za when you interact with our site. In this way, the information is secured - even as it gets submitted and received.

While a user is on an encrypted page, the 'lock' icon at the bottom of browsers, such as Internet Explorer and Netscape, becomes locked. To authenticate that you are in fact connecting to the Discovery.co.za site, you can double click on the 'lock' in the browser and look at the details of the digital certificate. Your password is your "key" to the site, without which you cannot enter.

top

In order to protect your password, it is important to not only keep it a secret, but to also create a password that cannot be worked out by someone else. For this reason we ask you to use a password that is at least 6 characters long and contains a numerical digit, for example, Password3. Because your password provides you with secure and confidential access to Discovery.co.za, it is of the utmost importance that you protect it and do not allow unauthorized use by others.

top

The only way for you to access your information is through the use of your secret password. So it is your responsibility to ensure that this password is kept completely protected. Discovery.co.za will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from your failure to comply with this responsibility.

top

Your confidential information will not be disclosed to any third parties without your prior permission of for reasons other than as set out herein. We wish to point out that we do share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers, but this is in no way linked to any personal information that can identify an individual person.

top

Whenever Discovery commissions other organisations to provide it with support services, they may be required to have access to your personal information to perform such services. The Discovery.co.za site may contain links to or from other sites. While Discovery tries to link only to sites that share the same highs standards and respect for privacy, Discovery cannot be held responsible for the content or security or privacy practices employed by other sites. It is recommended that you always read the privacy and security statements on such sites.

top

Discovery will not disclose personal information to anyone outside Discovery without your permission unless:

  * Discovery is compelled to do so by law or in terms of a court order;
  * it is in the public interest to do so;
  * it is necessary to protect our rights;

top

Different online services may have their own privacy and security policies because the nature of their service or products demands a deviation from Discovery's general policy. These specific policies will apply to and exclusively govern your use of the particular online service.

top

Discovery reserves the right to amend this privacy and security statement at any time. All amendments to this privacy and security statement will be posted on the website. Unless otherwise stated, the current version, shall supersede and replace all previous versions of this privacy and security statement.

If you have any questions about this privacy and security statement, please e-mail at [worldinfo@discovery.co.za](mailto:worldinfo@discovery.co.za)
